Ph.D. Student in Computer Science | Machine Learning | Data Science | Statistical Learning

□ (+1) 509-339-5866 | 🗷 ramesh.sah@wsu.edu | 🌴 www.rameshkrsah.github.io | 🖸 rameshKrSah | 🛅 rameshkrsah

"We are what we repeatedly do. Excellence, therefore, is not an act but a habit."

Summary _____

Currently studying Computer Science at Washington State University trying to solve problems in health care by developing novel machine learning algorithms and optimization processes. Interested in practical applications of machine learning to real-world problems.

Relevant and Transferable Skills

- Efficient at analyzing problems and think through for possible solutions
- Quick learner with focus on both research methodology and product innovations
- Excellent work ethics and time management skills

Skills_

Programming Languages Python, C, C++, Bash, R

Framework & Libraries PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, Scikit-Learn

Software Engineering Tools Git, vim, MEX

Databases MySQL

Experience

Washington State University

Pullman, WA.

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

May. 2019 - Current

- Investigated the effects of adversarial examples in wearable sensor systems used in health care applications. We showed how an adversary can craft adversarial examples and fool the underlying machine learning models. We published a conference paper with our approach, analysis, and results.
- Investigated the transferability of adversarial examples in wearable sensor systems from four novel different perspectives: 1) transferability between models, 2) transferability between subjects, 3) transferability across sensor body locations, and 4) transferability between datasets.
- Working to quantify, measure, and detect stress in real-time in alcohol-addicted individuals. We aim to build a mobile health system that can detect stress and provide interventions such as music therapy, games, and inspirational texts to prevent alcohol dependent people from relapsing.
- Developing an Android app to collect inertial and image data for a human in loop activity monitoring system for health care.

Washington State University

Pullman, WA.

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT

Aug. 2018 - May. 2019

- Helped students by answering their questions in several Computer Science courses.
- Graded home works and exams and gave lectures in class with 150 students.
- · Courses: Introduction to Machine Learning, Data Structures and Algorithms, Software Development, and Computer Architecture.

Real Time Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Patan, Nepal

FIRMWARE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Dec. 2016 - May. 2019

- Wrote efficient and resilient C code for products ranging from smart home, IoT, queue management systems, weather monitoring systems, and flood/landslide warning systems.
- Used machine learning algorithms in IoT applications such as smoke detector, vehicle accident monitoring system, and anti-theft system to prevent theft of solar panels installed in remote weather monitoring stations.

FEBRUARY 3, 2021 RAMESH K. SAH · RÉSUMÉ

Real Time Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Patan, Nepal

FIRMWARE SOFTWARE INTERN

Aug. 2016 - Dec. 2016

• Developed a prototype system to detect earthquake using off-the-shelf accelerometer. The system was designed to detect P and S waves and act as an earthquake monitoring and early-warning system.

Education _____

Washington State University (WSU)

Pullman, WA

DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY, COMPUTER SCIENCE

August 2018 - May 2023 (expected)

- · Research and development of machine learning algorithms and cyber physical system for mobile health.
- Cumulative GPA: 3.81 on a 4.00 scale
- Relevant Coursework: Machine Learning, Data Science, Graph Theory, Embedded Systems, Optimization in Networks, Algorithmics, Statistical Theory

Kathmandu University (KU)

Dhulikhel, Nepal

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

March 2012 - September 2016

- Final Year Project: Comparative Analysis of Routing Protocols for Wireless Body Area Networks.
- Cumulative GPA: 3.89 on a 4.00 scale
- Relevant Coursework: C, C++, Electronics, Numerical Analysis, Calculus

Publications

Adar: Adversarial Activity Recognition in Wearables

Westminister, CO, USA

The 38^{th} IEEE/ACM International Conference on Computer Aided Design (ICCAD)

Nov 4-7, 2019

Adversarial Transferability in Wearable Sensor Systems

ARXIV PREPRINT - UNDER REVIEW

Mobile Health for Alcohol Recovery and Relapse Prevention

Washington D.C., USA

The 5^{th} IEEE/ACM International Conference on Connected Health: Applications, Systems and Engineering

Dec 2020

TECHNOLOGIES

Honors & Awards

Recipient of Graduate and Professional Student Association (GPSA) student travel grant, Washington State

University

2018 Awarded full-time RA/TA scholarship, Washington State University

2015 Recipient of ERASMUS Mundus INTACT student exchange scholarship, Kathmandu University

2016 Merit Scholarship for Academic Excellence, Kathmandu University

First Prize in Society of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (SEEE) Circuit Competition, Kathmandu

2012 University

Open Source Projects _____

Adar

TENSORFLOW IMPLEMENTATION OF THE PAPER, "ADAR: ADVERSARIAL ACTIVITY RECOGNITION IN WEARABLES"